<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://criticalcarelab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://criticalcarelab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-22T06:06:18+00:00</updated><id>https://criticalcarelab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Critical Care Research Lab</title><subtitle>We study the microvascular physiology of critical illness to improve the diagnosis, monitoring, and treatment of patients in intensive care. Our work integrates biomedical optics, advanced signal analysis, and translational animal models to bridge the gap between bench and bedside.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Celebrating MSc Thesis Defenses – Amirali &amp;amp; Isuru</title><link href="https://criticalcarelab.github.io/2025/08/22/post-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating MSc Thesis Defenses – Amirali &amp;amp; Isuru" /><published>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-22T06:05:46+00:00</updated><id>https://criticalcarelab.github.io/2025/08/22/post-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://criticalcarelab.github.io/2025/08/22/post-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are delighted to share exciting news from the <strong>Critical Care Research Lab</strong>! This Summer 2025, two of our graduate students, <strong>Amirali Mirsajadi</strong> and <strong>Isuru Herath</strong>, successfully defended their Master’s theses and are graduating with MSc degrees in <strong>Biomedical Engineering</strong>.</p>

<p>Amirali’s thesis focused on advancing individualized hemodynamic monitoring in critically ill patients. Using high-resolution Near-Infrared Spectroscopy (hr-NIRS), he developed methods to derive optimal mean arterial pressure (MAPopt) from skeletal muscle signals and to quantify microvascular function with wavelet-based metrics. His findings highlight the potential for more personalized and precise resuscitation strategies in intensive care.</p>

<p>Isuru’s thesis explored physiological coherence between the brain and skeletal muscle microcirculation, also using hr-NIRS with sophisticated wavelet analysis. His work revealed disrupted organ-to-organ vascular communication in critical illness and identified coherence patterns linked with patient outcomes. These insights open the door to new biomarkers for personalized ICU monitoring and risk stratification.</p>

<p>We congratulate both Amirali and Isuru on their outstanding research contributions and wish them continued success as they embark on the next stage of their careers. The Critical Care Research Lab is proud of their achievements and looks forward to seeing the impact of their work in the field of critical care and biomedical engineering.</p>]]></content><author><name>critical-care-research-lab</name></author><category term="biomedical engineering" /><category term="critical care" /><category term="thesis defense" /><category term="graduation" /><category term="uofm" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are delighted to share exciting news from the Critical Care Research Lab! This Summer 2025, two of our graduate students, Amirali Mirsajadi and Isuru Herath, successfully defended their Master’s theses and are graduating with MSc degrees in Biomedical Engineering.]]></summary></entry></feed>